（翻页）
(page whirring)
- 在深入研究基于字符的标记化之前，
- Before diving in character-based tokenization,
理解为什么这种标记化很有趣
understanding why this kind of tokenization is interesting
需要了解基于单词的标记化的缺陷。
requires understanding the flaws of word-based tokenization.
如果你还没有看过第一个视频
If you haven't seen the first video
基于词的分词
on word-based tokenization
我们建议你在观看此视频之前检查一下。
we recommend you check it out before looking at this video.
好的，让我们看一下基于字符的标记化。
Okay, let's take a look at character-based tokenization.
我们现在将文本拆分为单个字符，
We now split our text into individual characters,
而不是文字。
rather than words.
语言中通常有很多不同的词，
There are generally a lot of different words in languages,
而字符数保持较低。
while the number of characters stays low.
首先让我们看一下英语，
To begin let's take a look at the English language,
它估计有 170,000 个不同的词，
it has an estimated 170,000 different words,
所以我们需要非常大的词汇量
so we would need a very large vocabulary
包含所有单词。
to encompass all words.
使用基于字符的词汇表，
With a character-based vocabulary,
我们可以只用 256 个字符，
we can get by with only 256 characters,
其中包括字母、数字和特殊字符。
which includes letters, numbers and special characters.
即使是有很多不同字符的语言
Even languages with a lot of different characters
就像中文可以有字典一样
like the Chinese languages can have dictionaries
多达 20,000 个不同的字符
with up to 20,000 different characters
但超过 375,000 个不同的单词。
but more than 375,000 different words.
所以基于字符的词汇
So character-based vocabularies
让我们使用更少的不同标记
let us use fewer different tokens
比基于单词的分词词典
than the word-based tokenization dictionaries
否则我们会使用。
we would otherwise use.
这些词汇也比较全
These vocabularies are also more complete
比他们基于单词的词汇对应物。
than their word-based vocabularies counterparts.
由于我们的词汇表包含所有字符
As our vocabulary contains all characters
用在一种语言中，甚至是看不见的词
used in a language, even words unseen
在分词器训练期间仍然可以分词，
during the tokenizer training can still be tokenized,
因此词汇表外的标记将不那么频繁。
so out-of-vocabulary tokens will be less frequent.
这包括正确标记化的能力
This includes the ability to correctly tokenize
拼错的单词，而不是丢弃它们
misspelled words, rather than discarding them
立即未知。
as unknown straight away.
然而，这个算法也不完美。
However, this algorithm isn't perfect either.
直觉上，字符不成立
Intuitively, characters do not hold
一个词所能包含的信息量。
as much information individually as a word would hold.
例如，“让我们” 包含更多信息
For example, "Let's" holds more information
比它的第一个字母 “l”。
than it's first letter "l".
当然，并非所有语言都如此，
Of course, this is not true for all languages,
作为一些语言，比如基于表意文字的语言
as some languages like ideogram-based languages
有很多信息保存在单个字符中，
have a lot of information held in single characters,
但对于其他像基于罗马的语言，
but for others like roman-based languages,
该模型必须理解多个标记
the model will have to make sense of multiple tokens
一次获取以其他方式持有的信息
at a time to get the information otherwise held
一句话。
in a single word.
这导致了基于字符的分词器的另一个问题，
This leads to another issue with character-based tokenizers,
他们的序列被翻译成非常大量
their sequences are translated into very large amount
模型要处理的标记数。
of tokens to be processed by the model.
这会对上下文的大小产生影响
And this can have an impact on the size of the context
该模型将随身携带，并会减小尺寸
the model will carry around, and will reduce the size
我们可以用作模型输入的文本，
of the text we can use as input for our model,
这通常是有限的。
which is often limited.
这种标记化虽然存在一些问题，
This tokenization, while it has some issues,
在过去看到了一些非常好的结果
has seen some very good results in the past
所以在接近时应该考虑
and so it should be considered when approaching
解决问题的新问题
a new problem as it solves issues
在基于词的算法中遇到。
encountered in the word-based algorithm.
（翻页）
(page whirring)